A Finding Aid to the Reginald R. Isaacs Papers, circa 1842-1991, bulk 1928-1991, in the Archives of American Art AAA.isaaregi
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1940-1986, undated; Series 7; 2 Linear feet Boxes 3-4, 22
  - Lectures and Articles, circa 1940-1986; 7.1
    - "Planning for the Future," Discussion Panel for the 9th Annual Conferma Presentation, Boston, 1964 November - (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - "Human Relations", circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - "Toward a New City," Lecture at the Walker Art Center, Minneapolis, 1965 September (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - "Gropius and the City," Lecture Introductions for the University of Washington, University of British Columbia, and University of Rhode Island, 1966 February (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - "Reconnaissance" - Regarding the Establishment of a Masters in Regional Planning Program at Ohio University, Athens, Ohio, 1967 February (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - "Problems & Resources of Man's Environment," Putney School Spring Conference "Man and His Environment," Putney, Vermont, 1967 April (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - "Gropius y la Ciudad," Lecture for the Division de Estudios Superiores Escuela Nacional de Arquitectura, Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico, 1968 September (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Gropius and the City, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 67-68)
    - "Walter Gropius and the City," Lecture for Ball State University, Muncie, Indiana, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - "Walter Gropius - A Tribute," with the introduction of Ise Gropius, Chicago Chapter American Institute of Architects; and "Walter Gropius, 1883-1969," Faculty of Design Meeting Minutes, Harvard University (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - "National Urban Growth Policies," speech given by Luis Ferre, Governor of Puerto Rico at the National Housing Conference, 1970 February (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Gropius Y La Ciudad, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - "Proposed Program for Doctor of Philosophy - Florida State University," report, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - "The Common Good", 1971 January (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - "Some Comments on the City and Regional Planning Program at Auburn University," with M. Ismail Serageldin, 1971 January (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - "Planning for the Future", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - "The Art, Education and Responsibility of Planners - A tribute to John Merriman Gaus and Howard W. Odum, Sr.," with M. Ismail Serageldin, 1971-72 (Box 3, Folder 77-81)
    - Society of American Registered Architects regrading education, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - The Making of Cities, by Dennis Sharp, reviewed by Isaacs and M. Ismail Serageldin, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Verhandlungen des XXXVIII. Internationalen Amerikanistenkongresses Band IV Symposium title The Process of Urbanization in America Since its Origins to the Present Time Organized by Jorge E. Erwin, Walter Palm and Richard Schaedel, Reviewed by Isaacs, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - "The Bauhaus - Utopia?", circa 1975 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Laudation-Ise Gropius' 80th Birthday, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - "The Urban Prospect: Future of the Small American City," Symposium, Lafayette College, Easton, Pennsylvania, 1978 February (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - "Walter Gropius (1883-1969)," for MacMillan Encyclopedia, c. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - "Gropius - Harvard Teacher", c. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 89-90)
    - "The Man Gropius", c. 1984 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Early Twentieth Century Sociologists as Planners: A Rare Breed? A Prelude to Research, by Thomas H. Jenkins, reviewed by Isaacs, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - "Walter Gropius, Architect, Teacher, Humanist, Philosopher," Lecture for the Cambridge Historical Society, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - "Civil Defense Needs in Site Selection for Hospitals," undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Introduction of Stuart Hughes, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Rationalization of Research on Housing and Urban Problems, by Richard Ratcliff, Reviewed by Isaacs, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lecture on Michael Reese Hospital, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Planning as a Profession - A Discussion," undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "Planning in Education and Practice," undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Socio-Economic and Political Problems - Social Aspects of Planning," undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Urban design Lecture, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Urban Land: Some Proposals for Its Use," undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Card File and Lists of Reginald Isaacs' Writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 10-14)
    - Lists of Reginald Isaacs' Writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Bibliography of Writings by Others, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Oversized Photograph, "The Rape of the Lake", circa 1949 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Entries, undated; 7.2
    This subseries contains biographical entries for the following individuals: Patrick Abercrombie; Franz Adickes; Josef Albers; Alfred Arndt; Otto Bartning; Herbert Bayer; Walter Curt Behrendt; Peter Behrens; Hendrik Petrus Berlage; Max Bill; Otto Eduard Leopold Von Bismarck; Serge Ivan Chermayeff; Wells Wintemute Coates; Arthur Coleman Comey; James Bryant Conant; Lucio Costa; Jack Cotton; John Dewey; Thomas Stearns Eliot; Friedrich Engels; Lyonel Feininger; Johann Gottlieb Fichte; Philip Sargeant Florence; Fountains and Waterfeatures; Edwin Maxwell Fry; Patrick Geddes; Frederick Gibberd; Sigfried Giedion; David Gilly; Friedrich Gilly; Johann Wolfgang Von Goethe; Ise Frank Gropius; Manon Gropius; Martin Carl Philipp Gropius; Walther Gropius; George Grosz; Knut Hamsun; Gustav Hassenpflug; Werner Hebebrand; Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel; Fritz Hesse; Moses Hess; Theodor Heuss; Ludwig Hilberseimer; Paul Hindemith; William Graham Holford; Sutemi Horiguchi; Ebenezer Howard; Joseph Fairman Hudnut; Aldous Leonard Huxley; Julian Sorrell Huxley; Reginald Roderic Isaacs; Wassily Kandinsky; Immanuel Kant; Oskar Kokoschka; Ferdinand Lassalle; Le Corbusier; Karl Liebknecht; Adolf Loos; Wassili Luckhardt; Rosa Luxemburg; Fritz Mackenson; Gerhard Marcks; Sven Gottfrid Markelius; Sir John Leslie Martin; Karl Marx; Ernst May; Erich Mendelsohn; Adolf Meyer; Hannes Meyer; Laszlo Moholy-Nagy; Sir Oswald Ernald Mosley; Lewis Mumford; Hermann Muthesius; Friedrich Naumann; Ernst Neufert; Richard Joseph Neutra; Friedrich Nietzsche; Karl Ernst Osthaus; Jacobus Johannes Pieter Oud; Hans Poelzig; John Craven Pritchard; Walther Rathenau; Sir Herbert Read; James M. Richards; Henry Hobson Richardson; Philip Rosenthal; Bertrand Arthur William Russell; Hans Bernhard Scharoun; Johann Christoph Friedrich Von Schiller; Karl Friedrich Schinkel; Gottfired Semper; Jose Luis Sert; Morton Phillip Shand; Thomas Sharp; Georg Simmel; Adolf Sommerfeld; Mart Stam; Gordon Stephenson; Igor Stravinsky; Louis Henri Sullivan; Bruno Taut; Leo Tolstoy (Count Lev Nikolayevich); Ferdinand Tonnies; Sir Raymond Unwin; Henri Van De Velde; Wilhelm Von Humboldt; Martin Wagner; Richard Wagner; Max Weber; Alma Mahler Gropius Werfel; Wilhalm I (Wilhelm Friedrich Ludwig); Wilhalm II (Friedrich Wilhelm Viktor Albert); Louis Wirth; and Frank Lloyd Wright.
    The entries are arranged alphabetically.
    - Biographical Entries, Lists/Notes (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Biographical Entries, A-W (Box 4, Folder 18-34)
  - Publications, 1944-1974; 7.3
    This subseries contains published copies of other published writings by Isaacs. The material generally focuses on the fields of planning and architecture, and the works and teachings of Walter Gropius. Some of the writings have been translated into Spanish and German.
    Publications are arranged chronologically by publication date. Often, two or more publications are filed in one folder.
    - "Traffic and Residential Real Estate," Federal Home Loan Bank Review, with Victor H. Bringe, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - "Planning Review of 1944," Planning and Civic Comment, with G. Holmes Perkins and Victor Bringe, vol. 11, no. 1; "Educational, Cultural, and Recreational Services," The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, vol. 242, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - "Traffic and Residential Real Estate;" "City Region and Regionalism," by Robert E. Dickinson, Reviewed by Isaacs, Journal of Land Economics; "The "Neighborhood Concept," Journal of Housing, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - "The Neighborhood Theory," Journal of the American Institute of Planners, vol. XIV, no. 2; "The Neighborhood Concept in Theory and Application," Land Economics; Communities for Better Living, by James Dahir, and Community Organization and Planning, Arthur Hillman, Reviewed by Isaacs, Journal of Housing; Children and the City, by Olga Adams, Published by Isaacs, 1948-1952 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - The Core of the City: A Pilot Study of Changing Land Uses in Central Business Districts, by John Rannells, reviewed by Isaacs, Journal of the American Statistical Association, vol. 52, no. 278; "Public Relations and Planning," Planning; "History: Effect on Tomorrow's Architecture," Architecture Plus; "Historia: su efecto sobre la arquitectura de futuro," Revista de la Facultad de Arquitectura, no. 3. Seti., 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - "Goals for Planning," Audit, vol. II, no. 4; Consideraciones sobre la cultura de Puerto Rico en la planificacion, Ediciones Rvmbos; "La Estetica del Arte Metropolitano," Orbanismo, vol I, no. 2; "Bibliotecas y Documentacion para la planeacion," Orbanismo, vol I, no. 3, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - "Factores Culturales en la planeacion," Orbanismo, vol. I, no. 4; "Metas Ideales para el Planeamiento," Revista Mexicana de Sociologia, vol. XXIV, no. 3; "La estetica del area metropolitana," Urbe, vol. 1, no. 4, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - "El concepto de la Unidad Vecinal en la teoria y en la practica," Revista de la Facultad de Arquitetura Universidad de la Republica, no. 4; Art in Latin American Architecture, by Paul F. Damaz, reviewed by Isaacs, Landscape Architecture; "Metas Ideales para el Planeamiento;" "Consideracioines sobre la cultura de Puerto Rico en la planificacion,", 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - "Metas Ideales para el Planeamiento;" "Kaduna Forum - an international forum," Architectural Association Quarterly; "Gropius and the City," Boston University Journal, vol. XVIII, no. 1, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - "The Art, Education and Responsibility of Planners," with M. Ismail Serageldin, The Place of Planning; Evaluation and Updating of the 1967 Study Design, Gulf Regional Planning Commission, Gulfport, Mississippi, 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - "Threshold to the Future," Profile '73; "The Making of Cities," Architectural Association Quarterly, vol. 5, no. 2; "Economic growth is just part of development," National Development/Modern Government; "Threshold to the Future," Profile '73, 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Teaching Files, circa 1954-1973; Series 8; 1 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Teaching files include material for the courses Isaacs taught at Harvard University's Graduate School of Design in the Departments of City and Regional Planning and Landscape Architecture, and include his miscellaneous faculty committee files. These files also contain documentation of the courses Isaacs taught while a guest lecturer at the University of Puerto Rico for the Graduate Program in Planning, 1969-1970. Files found in this series may contain course outlines, lecture and discussion notes, reading lists, and course projects.
  - Methods in Planning (Box 4, Folder 46-59)
  - Metropolitan and Regional Areas Planning, Development and Administration in the United States and Other Countries (Box 4, Folder 60-68)
  - Community Facilities and Services (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Advanced Theory and Method of Planning, circa 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Planning, Development and Administration in the United States and Other Countries, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dept. of City and Regional Planning, An Experiment in Pedagogy, Evaluation, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Implementation of City and Regional Planning in Developing Countries, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Functional Analysis and Policy Formulations, Area - Metropolitan Buenos Aires, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Miscellaneous Lists for Lecture and Seminar Topics, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Architectural Sciences, Housing Design, 19554 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dept. of Landscape Architecture and Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Regional Planning and Special Projects on Institutions, 1955, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dept. of Landscape Architecture, Regional Expression in Housing and Community Design, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Committee, Discussion of Proposal for a Laboratory of Regional Science, Memorandum; Essay: "Wistful Reflections on the Proposed Building for the Graduate School of Design;" Balanced Program Memorandum, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, Statements of Conscience on the War in Vietnam, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - University of Puerto Rico, Utopia and Ideal Society, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - University of Puerto Rico, Goals and Values for Planning, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - University of Puerto Rico, Planner's Responsibility to Urban Society, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Works of Art, 1965-1967,undated; Series 9; 3 Folders Box 5, OV 23
  This series includes a sketch in colored pencil by Max Bill; a pen and ink bookplate by Hans Maria Wingler; a water color poster by Gary M. Tierney announcing Isaacs's lecture "Walter Gropius and the City;" a caricature of Isaacs sculling by an unidentified artist; and two pen and ink sketches of Walter Gropius by Christian Hofer that were previously filmed on Reel 2331, Frames 488 to 491.
  - Artwork by Bill, Wingler, Tierney and Unidentified, 1965-1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Artwork by Christian Hofer, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Oversized Watercolor Poster by Gary M. Tierney announcing Isaacs's lecture "Walter Gropius and the City" (Box OV 23)
- Scrapbooks, 1929-1969, Series 10; 2 Folders Box 5
  This series contains two scrapbooks. The first includes correspondence and printed material regarding Isaacs's appointment as the Charles Dyer Norton Professor of Regional Planning. The second contains obituaries and eulogies for Walter Gropius.
  - Reginald Isaacs at Harvard University, 1929-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Obituaries and Eulogies for Walter Gropius, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Printed Material, 1842-1844, 1913-1986, undated; Series 11; 0.5 Linear feet Box 5
  This series includes exhibition catalogs and announcements, including a 1936 catalog for the Twenty-Second Annual Twin City Art Exhibit at the Institute of Arts in Minneapolis; news clippings, lecture announcements, and commission reports relating to the Chicago Plan Commission; publicity material, programs, and reports from the Graduate School of Design at Harvard University; and general miscellaneous material including the Farmer's Almanac from 1842 and 1844, Rudolf Serkin's autograph from 1943, lecture announcements, and newspaper and magazine articles regarding architecture, engineering, planning, and other subjects.
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1936, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Chicago Plan Commission, Michael Reese Hospital, 1943, 1945-1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 21-25)
  - Harvard University, Graduate School of Design, 1941-1986 (Box 5, Folder 26-32)
  - General, 1842-1844, 1913, 1926, 1935-1985, undated (Box 5, Folder 33-46)
- Photographs, 1959-1981, undated; Series 12; 7 Folders Boxes 5, 22
  Photographs of Isaacs and his family include images of his wife, Charlotte Aldes Isaacs. Photographs of friends and associates include photos of Newton S. Friedman, the Cambridge Skating Club, Karl Carstens, and Hans Maria Wingler.
  - Portraits of Reginald Isaacs, 1963, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    Oversized portrait of Isaacs in Box 22, Folder 3.
  - Reginald Isaacs and Family, undated (Box 5, Folder 48-49)
  - Reginald Isaacs with Friends and Associates, 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous, Unidentified, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Works of Art by Pollock, Saltzman, Heiliger, Citreon, and Carter, 1959-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Sculptures of Walter Gropius, 1959-1966 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Oversized Portrait of Reginald Isaacs, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Walter Gropius Biography, circa 1800s-1991, undated; Series 13; 16 Linear feet Boxes 6-22, OV 23, MGP 1, 2, 4
  This series documents the research for, and the writing and publication of, Isaacs' two volume biography of Bauhaus architect, Walter Gropius, through research material collected and organized by Isaacs during the course of his work on the biography.
  The series is organized into seven subseries according to material type. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  13.1: Survey Responses, circa 1965
  13.2: Research and Bibliographic Material, circa 1883-1986, undated
  13.3: Drafts of Biography, circa 1972-1977, 1991
  13.4: Comments on the Biography, circa 1991, undated
  13.5: Publication Correspondence, 1969-1989
  13.6: Photographs and Illustrations for the Biography, circa 1800s-1983, undated
  13.7: Printed Material, 1912-1991, undated
  - Survey Responses, circa 1965; 13.1
    This subseries contains questionnaires for a survey that were distributed by Isaacs and returned to him by former students of Gropius at the Bauhaus and at Harvard University. In addition to the survey responses, there are also charts which summarize the data contained therein.
    - Bauhaus Graduates, Chart of Responses, circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Bauhaus Graduates, Responses, circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 2-34)
    - Harvard Bachelor of Architecture Graduates, Chart of Responses, circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Harvard Bachelor of Architecture Graduates, Responses, circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 36-38)
    - Harvard Master of Architecture Graduates, Chart of Responses, circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Harvard Master of Architecture Graduates, Responses, circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 40-47)
  - Research and Bibliographic Material, circa 1883-1986, undated; 13.2
    This subseries contains general research and bibliographic files compiled and organized by Isaacs for his work on the biography. The files contain correspondence, notes, writings, printed materials, and a few photographs. Many of the documents were created and/or authored by Walter Gropius and Ise Gropius. Large portions of these files are photocopies, although some originals can also be found; many are in German. Following is a list of the major subjects and names found in these files.
    Files are arranged alphabetical by name or subject heading.
    - Adler - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 6, Folder 48)
      Includes Alcher-School, Inge, 1957, 1959.
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 6, Folder 49)
      About building proposals.
    - Americans for Democratic Action - Arend, Herbert von (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Argan, Givlio Carlo (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Argentini, Antonio Amadeo - Augustyniak, Marian Z. (Box 6, Folder 52)
      Includes clippings about Arup, Ove, 1966.
    - Bach to Bartlett (Box 6, Folder 53)
      Includes correspondence between Reyner Banham and Ise Gropius about Bauhaus; and Alfred J. Barr, Jr., 1938.
    - Bartning, Otto, 1951-1957 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Barucki to Bauer (Box 6, Folder 55)
      Includes Fred Bassetti, 1947-1948.
    - Bauhaus, 1924-1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 56-60)
      Includes correspondence with Alvar Aalto, Alfred Barr, Donald C. Dunham, Heinrich Engel, Carola W. Giedion, Fritz Hesse, Herbert Hubner, Jane Fiske McCullough, William Wurster, notes and writings about the Bauhaus by Isaacs and others, and clippings.
    - Bauhaus Archiv, 1960-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1-7)
      Includes correspondence with Peter Hahn, Hans and Heidi Wingler, Christian Wolsdorff, exhibition announcements and clippings.
    - Bayer, Herbert and Joella, 1932-1981 (Box 7, Folder 8-14)
      Includes correspondence with Ise Gropius, writings by and about Herbert Bayer.
    - Behrens, Peter - Bellman (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Beneman, Maria, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Berg, Alban - Berlin (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Bernberger, Maschinen Fabrik - Beyer, 1964-1968, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Bibliographies Regarding Walter Gropius, undated (Box 7, Folder 19-21)
    - Bill, Max, 1945-1979 (Box 7, Folder 22-24)
      About the Hochschule fur Gestaltung also known as the "Ulm Bauhaus."
    - Black Mountain College - Bluhova (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Bochum University Competition, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Bogner - Boyd (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Brauneck - Britz-Buckow-Rudow (BBR) (Box 7, Folder 28)
      One BBR plat and one BBR map housed in OV 23.
    - Buenos Aires, Argentina - Bundesbaudirektion (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Büro-Organisation, 1928-1931 (Box 7, Folder 30-35)
      Includes memos, contract drafts, brochures, and clippings about office organization.
    - Busch-Reisinger Museum, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 36-38)
      About the Gropius Archive and exhibition.
    - Campbell - Carter (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Chermayeff, Serge, 1948-1977 (Box 7, Folder 40-42)
      About Institute of Design, Congres Internationaux D'Architecture Moderne (CIAM) and Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) includes correspondence with Ivan Chermayeff, Jose Luis Sert, and Konrad Wachsmann.
    - Chilar - Clark (Box 7, Folder 43)
      Includes Clarenbach, Dietrich, 1968, about the monument to those killed in the Kapp Putsch - Denkmal Fur der Marzgefallen, Weimar.
    - Clay, General Lucius, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 44)
      Includes Gropius' report as Advisor to Clay on the reconstruction of Germany.
    - Cleveland, Ohio, Tower East (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Coates, Wells, 1937-1938, 1953, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 46)
      Includes correspondence with Jose Luis Sert and Isaacs.
    - On Collaboration, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Collein - Colwell (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Computer Conference: Architecture and the Computer (Box 7, Frame 49)
    - Conant, James Bryant, 1938-1978 (Box 7, Folder 50-52)
    - Conant, Kenneth, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Congres Internationaux D'Architecture Moderne (CIAM), 1938-1955 (Box 7, Folder 54-65)
      Includes correspondence with Fred Forbat, Sigfried Giedion, Julian Huxley, Le Corbusier, Stamo Papadaki, Jose Luis Sert, Helena and Szymon Syrkus, and Jaqueline Tywhitt, a copy of Grille CIAM d'Urbanisme, 1948, and 1949 meeting dossier.
    - Conklin - Costa (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Cotton, Jack, 1961-1972 (Box 7, Folder 67)
      About Monico Piccadilly Circus, London.
    - Council for the Aging, Boston - Currie (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - DADD - Danilevskil (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Davison, Robert L., 1928-1943, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 70-71)
      Includes correspondence with Josef Albers and Herbert Bayer.
    - Dearstyne, Howard, 1955-1968 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Deiters - Despotopolous (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Deutschen Demokratischen Republic, 1964-1966, undated (Box 7, Folder 74-75)
      Includes Isaacs' correspondence with Christian Schadlich, and Hans Scharoun.
    - Diamantopulis - Docker, Richard (Box 7, Folder 76)
      Includes Docker re: "The Ring," 1951-1965.
    - Dollinger - Eberhard (Box 7, Folder 77)
      Includes Dorner, Alexander, 1947.
    - Ebert - Edson (Box 7, Folder 78)
      Includes Ebert, Wills re. the Berlin School, 1957, 1968.
    - Egbert, Donald Drew, 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Elliott - Engels (Box 7, Folder 80)
      Includes Eliot, T.S., 1940-1958 - Ise's correspondence with Eliot and Thorton Wilder.
    - Faquswerk - Feuchtwanger (Box 7, Folder 81)